### Contact

Flat 302, Shivarajya Apartment, Jagruti colony, Vivek Nagar, Vasmat Road, Parbhani. 431401 pwaykos1@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/prajwalwaykos (LinkedIn) prajtech.xyz (Personal)

### Top Skills

llm

Retrieval Augmented Generation WebSocket

### Certifications

SQL Masterclass: SQL for Data Analytics

SQL (Basic)

Computer Vision: Face Recognition Quick Starter in Python

Learning Java 11

ChatGPT Prompt Engineering for Developers

### **Publications**

Enhancing E-Learning Experiences: A Novel Approach to Personalized Course Recommendations

Hierarchical Forecasting for Counter Prediction: A New Approach to Workforce Management and Customer Satisfaction

Copyright: Number of Counters Problem

Blockchain-Based Academic Bank of Credit Management System for Higher Education: An Innovative Approach to Student Credentialing and Progression

# Prajwal Waykos

Exchange Student (Intern) in Al at Lima, Peru.

Pune, Maharashtra, India

## Summary

Embarking on a journey as a Data Science Intern, my narrative is woven with a commitment to AI research, leadership, and innovation. I excel in challenging environments, contributing significantly to patents and copyrights while consistently pushing the boundaries of what's possible in the field.

### Experience

UMA - Universidad María Auxiliadora Artificial Intelligence Intern March 2024 - Present (3 months) Lima, Peru

Internship in AI under student mobility program.

Jnanamarga Technologies
Generative AI Engineer intern
December 2023 - Present (6 months)
United States

Worked on companies GenAl products using Large Language models and OpenAl APIs

Softlander Consultants
Prompt Engineer Intern
December 2023 - March 2024 (4 months)
Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh, India

created a curriculum development system using FastAPI and Prompt engineering with ChatGPT APIs.

YoZu

11 months

Technical Lead Engineer
April 2023 - December 2023 (9 months)

Mumbai Metropolitan Region

Leading the Yozu product Backend. it is an EdTech product for students of class 6 to 10.

Machine Learning Engineer February 2023 - April 2023 (3 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

#### Eaton

Data science Intern
June 2023 - July 2023 (2 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Extracted data from companies design PDFs for generating training data for generative AI models

### **HCLTech**

1 year 11 months

Lead Research intern

August 2022 - June 2023 (11 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Developed a prototype for a research project that identifies mathematical equations in words and converts it to mathematical form

### Reseach and Development intern

August 2021 - July 2022 (1 year)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Prepared metadata as well as training data for mathematical expression extraction project

#### HTS

Research Intern

April 2022 - March 2023 (1 year)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

AI/ML Research intern at HTS Tech Solutions.

### FlexiEle

10 months

**SQL** Database Administrator

June 2022 - November 2022 (6 months)

Delhi, India

Developed multiple MySQL Queries, functions and Procedures for companies HRMS tool.

Chatbot Developer

February 2022 - May 2022 (4 months)

Delhi. India

Developed a chatbot for companies HRMS tool.

Underwater Autonomous Vehicle Research Group

1 year 1 month

Head of Artificial Intelligence

June 2022 - November 2022 (6 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Team member in Al Domain

November 2021 - June 2022 (8 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Google Cloud Skills Boost

Trainee

March 2022 - June 2022 (4 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Participated in Google Cloud Ready Facilitator Program. Completed 40

Assignments and Tutorials and achieved the ultimate milestone.

Bharat soft solutions

Artificial Intelligence Intern

October 2021 - March 2022 (6 months)

Pune, Maharashtra, India

Developed a chatbot which can narrate the outside world to ablind person.

Milaan Foundation

Data Entry Specialist

September 2021 - February 2022 (6 months)

Remote

Did basic Data entry from Excel to web

Education

Vishwakarma Institute of Information Technology

Bachelor of Technology - BTech, Artificial Intelligence and Data

Science · (March 2021 - April 2024)